

**David Sanchez** 

(Jose David Sanchez Aguilar)
Helping people to build the most
innovative solutions with technology.

Orlando, Florida, USA 🙃

+1 (425) 326-7927

dsanchezcr@outlook.com 

✓

<u>dsanchezcr</u> in

dsanchezcr 🖸

dsanchezcr 🖹

dsanchezcr.com @



Computer Systems Engineer with over 13 years of experience in the technology industry focused on software engineering and cloud adoption with experience in multiple disciplines (Engineering, Sales, Support and Marketing) and multiple industries.

Awarded as Microsoft Most Valuable Professional - Developer Technologies.

## **Skills**

#### **Tools & Technologies**

- Microsoft Azure
- Visual Studio
- Azure DevOps
- GitHub (GHEC & GHES)
- C#, .NET & ASP.NET
- SQL (MS SQL/SQL Azure)
- HTML5 (CSS & JS)
- Power Platform
- SharePoint

#### **Industry Knowledge**

- DevOps
- Agile Methodologies
- Technical Training
- Consultancy
- Content Strategery
- Sales Management
- Localization
- Identity & Access (IAM)
- Program Management

#### **Interpersonal (Soft Skills)**

- Active Listening
- Public Speaking
- Empathy
- Leadership
- Mentoring
- People Manager
- Conflict Management
- Problem solving
- Responsibility

# **Certifications**

#### **Microsoft**



















# GitHub







# Languages

• Spanish: Native.

• English: Fluent.

Portuguese: Limited.

# **Experience**

SEP 2022 - PRESENT

## **DevOps Consultant / Xebia | Xpirit, USA**

Xpirit part of Xebia is a Microsoft Gold Partner & GitHub Verified Partner. I joined a team of highly experienced consultants, experts in cloud transformation using Microsoft Azure, building high performance IT teams using DevOps, and creating Cloud Native Software.

OCT 2021 - SEP 2022

## Senior Program Manager - Localization / Microsoft, USA

Spanish & Portuguese localization for technical content to enabling & accelerating the consumption of the most relevant localized content to grow product adoption & usage globally.

APR 2021 - OCT 2021

# Senior Developer Advocate – Azure Maps / Microsoft, USA

I created and presented different technical content for Azure Geospatial APIs.













JAN 2018 - APR 2020

# Senior Product Marketing Manager – Azure App Innovation Microsoft, USA

I helped defining, validating, and creating a pipeline of end-to-end demo applications focused on Azure services for developers. Drove an agile process for demo development with multiple cross-company stakeholders for major Microsoft events and keynotes, supporting the demos delivering, including executive demo support and on-stage presentation. Worked broadly across Microsoft Azure engineering, marketing teams, and field stakeholders to create technical content (whitepapers, presentations, demo assets, labs and training material and videos).









FEB 2017 - DEC 2017

# Application Development Manager / Microsoft, Costa Rica

Technical delivery for Premier Support for Developers providing end-to-end managed support across the full Microsoft developer platform: on-premises, hybrid or in the cloud.

DEC 2015 - JAN 2017

## Sales Solution Professional - DX / Microsoft, Costa Rica

I provided technical solutions to customers regarding Microsoft Developer Tools and Technologies. I worked through evangelism, marketing, and sales to secure the successful

adoption of the application lifecycle management suite including Visual Studio, Team Foundation Server (Azure DevOps) and Microsoft Azure.

JUN 2015 - DEC 2015

# Senior Developer Advisor / Advisicon, Costa Rica

I delivered business and technical consulting services for LATAM based on strategic project management solutions using advanced project and portfolio management methodologies and tools, custom development, and comprehensive training.

AUG 2012 - JUL 2015

## Technical Trainer / Advance Learning, Costa Rica

I delivered multiple custom courses and Microsoft Official Courses (MOCs) to Advance Learning customers based on SharePoint and .NET

JAN 2015 - MAY 2015

## SharePoint Architect / Konrad Group, Costa Rica

Leading Architecture, Design, Implementation, Development and Deployment of SharePoint Solutions. Based on the Best Practices of the SharePoint Strategy and the ALM.

FEB 2012 - DEC 2014

# Small Business Owner & Technology Consultant Collaboration & Development Solutions, Costa Rica

I was the founder of a consulting services small business focused on SharePoint and .NET.

OCT 2010 - JAN 2012

# Software Support Engineer II / HP Enterprise, Costa Rica

I provided support as Level I & II for the following HP Enterprise Software:

APR 2010 - OCT 2010

# Software Developer / Universidad Latina de Costa Rica

Oracle database and forms developer in charge of optimizing internal reports and processes.

# **Education**

2013 - 2015 (UNFINISHED)

# Master Information Technology Management Universidad para la Cooperación Internacional, Costa Rica

2008 – 2011 (GRADUATED)

# Bachelor Computer Systems Engineering Universidad Latina de Costa Rica